### Joel Williams

305.495.3514

Joel.williams90@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/jwills2190

### **Summary:**

Noble Desktop Software Engineering Bootcamp student that has recently transitioned from technical recruitment with development experience in JavaScript, React, Node, Python, Bootstrap, Flexbox, HTML, CSS, and Django. I have an interest in full-stack development with JavaScript and/or Python and am actively seeking an opportunity to contribute to an organization. Having spent 8 years as a Technical Recruiter, I have had exposure to learning about different technologies/environments and have spoken with thousands of software engineers. I have learned that I am genuinely interested in software development and building interesting products and applications.

### **Professional Experience:**

### Noble Desktop Software Engineer Student

Oct 2023 - Mar 2024

- Transitioned from technical recruitment to software engineering after going through a comprehensive 5-month bootcamp with Noble Desktop.
- Spent 2 months, 35 hours/week specifically learning Vanilla JavaScript and I now feel proficient in writing and working with functions, loops, objects, variables, JSON, creating API's, methods, and conditional logic.
- Comfortable with CRUD basic operations, testing them in Postman, and working with MongoDB.
- Outside of the program, I have spent countless hours studying JavaScript, practicing leetcode problems and reading documentation on MDN Web Docs, scopes & closure, functions, and anything else I can get my hands on

## Code Red Partners - Remote Principal Recruiter

Nov 2022 - Sept 2023

Proven track record of building strong partnerships with both candidates and clients, fostering long-term

relationships based on trust and mutual success.

- Expertise in understanding the specific requirements and nuances of the industries (i.e. fintech, crypto, web3, defense, technology), effectively matching candidates' skills and experience with clients' needs.
- Utilize a consultative approach to partner with hiring managers, providing strategic guidance and insight throughout the recruitment process to ensure the right talent is sourced and placed.
- Demonstrate strong knowledge of the current technology landscape, staying up to date with industry trends and advancements to effectively assess candidates' suitability for various roles.

# Kofi Group – Remote IT Solutions Partner

**July 2022 - Nov 2022** 

- Full life cycle recruitment with a focus on partnering with seed through Series C startups and VC firms to hire technical talent.
- Source, pre-screen, interview, and submit Software Engineers, Cloud Engineers, Platform Engineers, Product Managers, and Full Stack Engineers.

## **Huntsource LLC - Charlotte, NC**

Jan 2021 - July 2022

### **Senior Technical Recruiter**

- Full life cycle recruitment of Solutions Architects, Cloud Security Architects & Engineers, Security Architects & Engineers, DevOps & DevSecOps Engineers, and Big Data Engineers.
- Lead the company in gross margin Q3 and Q4 of 2021, & Q1 and Q2 of 2022.
- Average \$11k in weekly contract gross margin plus 1 permanent placement a month averaging \$28k in gross margin.
- Placed 4 candidates within the first 4 months of being with the company (AWS Big Data Engineer, PHP Web Developer, Azure Platform Engineer, Application Security Engineer).

- Successfully sourced and delivered technology candidates to clients, contributing to the overall talent acquisition process.
- Filled open positions for network engineers, systems administrators, software engineers, and everything on the functional and business side.

### Eliassen Group – Tampa, FL (Remote) Technical Recruiter

Mar 2017 - Jan 2020

- Responsible for the end-to-end recruiting and hiring process for IT professionals on a national scale including initial contact, resume review, submittal, scheduling interviews, closing candidates on job offers.
- Averaged 9k in gross margin per week during majority of 2019 and the beginning of 2020.
- Reached a high of 35k in weekly gross margin with permanent placement.
- Ranked 1<sup>st</sup> in the office for active head count, 2<sup>nd</sup> in gross margin, and 1<sup>st</sup> in annual permanent placements.
- Specialize in the placement of QA Automation Engineers, DevOps Engineers, Network Engineers, Software Developers, Project Managers, and Technical Support Specialists.
- Contact an average of 25 active candidates per day about jobs with direct clients.
- Held world class level Net Promoter Score (NPS)

# Excite Health Partners – Tampa, FL Technical Recruiter

Sept 2015 - Mar 2017

- Identify and recruit qualified individuals for open positions.
- Proficient use of LinkedIn and Bond Adaptsuite ATS system to locate and keep track of consultants using notes and notifications to stay updated on recruitment and hiring processes.

#### **EDUCATION:**

**Bachelor of Healthcare Administration** August 2015

Florida International University, Miami, Florida Major: Health Services Administration